米高梅电影公司
哥伦比亚电影公司
龙森受伤了
Ronson's down.
需要马上抢救
He needs a medical evac.
东西还在吗 在不在
Where is it? Is it there?
硬盘拆掉了
Oh, the drive is gone.
你肯定吗
Are you sure?
肯定 请等一下
It's gone. Give me a minute.
一定在他们手里 快去找
They must have it. Get off to them.
我得给龙森包扎
I'm stabilizing Ronson.
我们没时间了
We don't have the time.
必须马上为他止血
I have to stop the bleeding.
先不要管他
Leave him!
看到他了
Have you got him?
那辆黑色奥迪
He is in the black Audi.
龙森怎么样
What about Ronson.
受伤了
He's been hit.
我们马上就会派出救援分队
I'm sending an emergency evacuation squad.
他们根本来不及
Well, that'll be too bloody late.
他发现了
Have they seen us?
救援分队将会在五分钟之内赶到
Medical Evac for Ronson, five minutes way.
没关系 反正用不着
It's allright? You'll wait using it.
那就索性都不用
I wasn't using that one either.
注意隐蔽
Keep your head down!
都给我闪开
Just get clear!
坦纳 什么方向
Tanner, which way?
向前 注意听我指挥
Keep going. I can direct you from here.
你们知道这件事非同小可
We both know what's at stake here.
我们不能失去那份名单
We can not afford to lose that list.
是 夫人
Yes, ma'am.
他们现在在哪儿
Where are they now?
好像是在大巴扎的房顶上
They're on the rooftop of the grand bazaar.
向左 有座桥 截住他
Take the left, there's a bridge. You can cut him off.
怎么回事
What happened?
他们上火车了 夫人
They're on the train, ma' am.
什么意思
What do you mean on the train?
他们在火车顶上
I mean they're on the top of the train.
你还不赶快去追
Well, get off to them, for God's sake.
即将超出跟踪范围
He's going out of range.
我们失去了目标
We've lost tracking. We are blind here.
情况怎么样 请回答   我还跟着他们
What's going on?    I'm still with them.
动用闭路电视 卫星定位 一切手段
Getting CCTV satellite, end of question.
什么声音
What was that?
好像是大众甲壳虫 夫人
VW Beetle, I think.
邦德
Bond.
他要断开车厢
He's uncoupling the cars.
007 你怎么样了
007, are you alright?
我换了个车厢
Just changing carriages.
情况如何 马上报告
What's going on? Report!
一时难以说清楚 夫人
It's rather hard to explain, ma'am.
007还在紧追不舍
007 is saying proceed.
前面已经无路可走 可能我只能到此为止了
This side here isn't much more road. I do not think I can go any further.
或许我可能击中他
I may have a shot.
目标不明确
It's not clean.
重复 目标不明确
Repeat. I did not have a clean shot.
前面有隧道 我将失去目标
There's a tunnel ahead. I'm gonna lose them.
还有其它的位置吗
Can you get into a better position?
不行 来不及了
Negative. There's no time.
马上给我开枪
Take the shot.
我让你开枪
I said, "Take the shot!"
不行 可能误伤邦德
Well, I can't. I may get Bond.
我让你开枪
Take the bloody shot.
击中邦德
Agent down.
丹尼尔・克雷格
天幕杀机
哈维尔・巴登
拉尔夫・费因斯
娜奥米・哈里斯
贝纳尼丝・玛尔洛
本・威士肖
罗里・金尼尔 奥拉・拉佩斯
阿尔伯特・芬尼
朱迪・丹琦 饰演 M
联合制片  安德鲁・诺克斯 大卫・珀普
选角导演 黛比・威廉姆斯      片头设计 丹尼尔・克雷曼
特效及微缩模型特效总监 克里斯・柯博德
特效协调 加里・鲍威尔
第二摄制组导演 亚历山大・维特
服装设计  简妮・泰米姆
剪辑  斯图尔特・贝尔德 凯特・贝尔德
摄影  罗杰・迪金斯
美术指导  丹尼斯・加斯纳
音乐  托马斯・纽曼
天幕落演唱者 阿黛尔
作曲 阿黛尔 和 保罗・艾沃斯
执行制片人 卡勒姆・麦克杜格尔
编剧  尼尔・普维斯 罗伯特・韦德 约翰・洛根
制片人  迈克尔・G・威尔森  芭芭拉・布洛克利
导演  萨姆・门德斯
特别鸣谢
参考字幕作者：白眉鹰王    协助双语合并：x115088
伦敦  军情六处
讣告：国防部高级官员，皇家海军志愿后备队指挥官，圣米迦勒及圣乔治三等勋爵士，
詹姆斯・邦德在土耳其执行任务期间失踪，据信已被杀害
感觉像是去校长办公室
It's like going into the headmaster study.
新官上任 例行公事而已
It's new chairman's just a standard procedure.
这简直就是浪费我的时间
Bloody waste of my time, that's what I'd call it.
很抱歉 第一次见面
I'm sorry to have to deal with such...
就跟你讨论如此棘手的问题
a delicate subject at our first encounter...
不过
But...
我必须坦诚相见
I have to be frank with you.
我觉得这样最好
And that would be a good idea.
首相有点担心
The Prime Minister is concerned.
请转告他 我的特工都非常尽职尽责
You can tell him my operatives are pursuing every avenue.
你考虑过撤回那些特工吗
Have you considered pulling up the agents?
我考虑过一切可能
I've considered every option.
对不起 听着像是在回避问题
Forgive me, but that sounds like an evasion.
对不起 为什么叫我到这儿来
Forgive me, but why am I here?
三个月前 你弄丢了一块计算机硬盘
Three months ago you lost the computer drive
那里面保存着全世界几乎所有
containing the identity of almost every NATO agent
打入恐怖组织内部的北约特工名单
embedded in terrorist organizations across the globe.
甚至我们的盟国都不知道
A list which, in the eyes of our allies,
我们有那份名单
never existed.
恕我直言 我想你知道你为什么来这儿
So, if you'll forgive me, I think you know why you're here.
这就是所谓的社会监督
How you should call it, a civilian oversight?
不 我们称之为
No, what we call this is...
退休计划
a retirement planning.
国家对你以及你多年来的工作
Your country has only the highest respect for you
给予高度评价
and your many years of service.
现任职务结束后
When your current posting is completed,
你将获得麦克乔治大十字勋章的崇高荣誉
you'll be awarded to GCMG with full honors.
祝贺你
Congratulations.
你想要炒我
You're firing me?
不 夫人 两个月后你才会自愿退休
No, ma'am, I'm here to oversee the transition period...
在这之前的这段过渡期由我负责接管
leading to your voluntary retirement in two months' time.
你的接班人尚未任命 所以还请你
Your successor has yet to be appointed, so we'll be asking you...
我不是傻瓜 马洛瑞
I'm not an idiot, Mallory.
我知道我不会永远在位
I know I can't do this job forever.
但是我绝对不会在有史以来
But I'll be damned if I'm going to leave the department
最困难的时刻离开岗位
in worst shape than I found it.
夫人 你干得不错
M... you've had a great run.
应该体面的收场
You should leave with dignity.
让体面见鬼去吧
Go to hell with dignity.
我不会半途离开
I'll leave when the job's done.
喂
Yes?
现在
Now?
军需官报告 夫人
Main alert from Q Robson,
有人正试图解密日前失窃的硬盘
trying to decrypt the stolen hard drive.
正在查找信号来源
We are tracing the encryption signal.
我们已经定位了
Localizing now.
信号中心在英国
It's sent here in the UK.
伦敦
London.
我们必须马上返回基地
Get to inspect the basis as soon as possible.
信号出自军情六处
It's coming from MI6.
什么
What?
数据包已经链接到了我们的网络
The data back, it is linking to our network.
并且已经穿透了我们的防火墙
Corrupted. This is behind our firewall.
应该关闭系统 夫人
We should shut down.
不 继续跟踪
track it.
必须弄清它的出处
We have to know where it's coming from.
去掉文件头 继续跟踪
Strip the head and try the source.
他们怎么会进入我们的系统
How the hell it entered in our system?
立刻查找源头
Getting a trace right now.
好像
lt appears
好像出自您的电脑 夫人
It is your computer, ma'am.
马上关机
Shut it down.
什么意思
What is this?
看在上帝的份上
For God's sake!
马上给我闪开
Just get out of the way.
你不认识这辆车吗    车辆不能通过 夫人
Don't you recognize the car?   Madam...
这里是CNN突发新闻
This is CNN Breaking News.
紧急救援人员正在试图评估损失
Emergency crews are still attempting to assess
调查人员也在查找线索
the damage as investigators hunt for leads
看来这是一次发生在伦敦市中心的重大恐怖袭击事件
In what now appears to be a major terrorist attack, in the heart of London.
目前还没有声称对此事负责
No one has yet claimed responsibility, for what sources are calling.
有消息称 这是一次网络恐怖份子针对英国情报机关的攻击
A possible Cyber Terrorist attack, on the British Secret Service.
此前报道表明 至少有6人死亡 多人受伤
Early reports from the scene, indicate at least 6 dead.
伤者已经在爆炸发生后不久 很快被送往当地医院
Many more injured, with victims being evacuated to local Hospitals.
进行全面救治
Within minutes of the explosion
我一定要找到罪魁祸首
I'm going to find who ever did this.
你跑到哪儿去了
Where the hell have you been?
去享受死亡
Enjoying death.
特工007前来报到
007, reporting for duty.
为什么不打电话
Why didn't you call?
没收到明信片
Didn't you get the postcard?
你也该去体验一下
You should try it sometimes.
远离现实 会获得新的视角
Get away from it all, it really lends perspective.
是不是因为没酒喝了才回来
Run out of drink. Were you awarded, eh?
你是怎么说的
What it was you said?
马上给我开枪
Take the bloody shot.
我只能跟着感觉走
I made a judgement call.
你应该相信 我可以完成任务
should have trusted me to finish the job.
但我的责任 是在失去你
It was the possibility of losing you...
和失去更多的人之间取舍
or the certainty of losing all those other agents.
我只能做出那样的决定 你很清楚
I made the only decision I could and you know it.
我觉得你乱了方寸
I think you've lost your nerve.
你想要我怎么样 向你道歉
What do you expect, a bloody apology?
你知道游戏规则 你干这行已经很久了
You know the rules of the game. You've been playing it long enough.
我也是
We both have.
也许太久了
Maybe too long.
那倒未必
Speak for yourself.
龙森没挺过来 对吗
Ronson didn't make it, did he?
是的
No.
这是宿命
So, this is it.
我们该退出舞台了
We're both played out.
既然如此 你为什么回来
Well, if you believed that, why did you come back?
问得好
Good question.
因为我们受到了攻击
Because we are under attack...
因为你知道我们需要你
and you know we need you.
是的
Well, I'm here.
首先你要了解情况
You'll have to be debriefed...
证明你适合执行任务
and declared fit for active service.
只有通过考察 你才能回来工作
You're gonna return to duty when you've passed the tests.
所以不可掉以轻心
So take them seriously.
眼下你需要洗个澡
The shower might be an order.
我得先回去换衣服
I'm going home and change.
哦 你的公寓卖掉了
Oh, we sold your flat.
你的东西都在仓库里
Put your things into storage.
像你这样的
Standard procedure...
没有亲属的未婚人士 死后都会照此办理
on the death of an unmarried employee with no next of kin.
你该打个电话
You should have called.
我去找家饭店
I'll find a hotel.
你不住这儿对大家都好
Well, you're bloody will not sleep in here.
袭击者进入环境控制系统
They attacked into the environmental control system
锁定安全协议 然后打开了煤气
locked out the safety protocols and have turned on the gas.
这一切简直不可思议
Well, that should have been impossible.
最要命的是 他们打开了M夫人的文件
I was told that they have hacked into our files.
知道了她的安排
They knew her appointments.
还知道她不在大楼里
They knew she would be out of the building.
他们没想除掉她
They weren't targeting her.
只想给她点颜色看
They wanted us to see it.
这是在哪儿 坦纳
Where are we, lieutenant?
新办公楼
New digs.
老办公楼容易受到战略攻击
The old building was declared strategically vulnerable.
这不是危言耸听
That's putting it mildly.
那个家伙能够突破英国最绝密的计算机系统
Their aim is to breach the most secured computer system in Britain.
我们已经处在战争的边缘了
So we are at war with them now.
这是丘吉尔二战时期的指挥所
This is part of Churchill's bunker.
我们已经发现了18世纪的地下通道
Some of these tunnels are dating back to the 18th century.
很有趣 如果没有老鼠的话
Quite fascinating, if it wasn't for the rats.
我何时能见M夫人
When do I see M?
明天就可以
Tomorrow, you'll see M...
也许还能见到马洛瑞先生
and Mallory too if you're lucky.
马洛瑞是谁
Who is Mallory?
英国情报和安全委员会新任主席
The new chairman of the Intelligence and Security Committee.
风度翩翩 我想你一定会和他一见如故的
A charming man, I think. You and him will really gonna hit it off.
军情六处欢迎你
Welcome to the new MI6.
我们试图跟踪那台计算机的信息 但是
We've have attempted to trace the computer message, but...
它采用非对称安全算法发送
it was sent by an asymmetrical security algorithm...
在全球无数台服务器中
with the chance to signal all over the globe
跳来跳去
through thousands of different servers.
眼下他们已经取得了M夫人的代码
And now that they've accessed M's code,
解密那份文件只是迟早的事
it's only a matter of time before they are able to decrypt the list.
军需官正在分析那幅图片 目前没有结果
Q branch has been analyzing pictures. But so far, nothing.
感觉是M夫人的熟人所为
General feeling it's probably something from her past.
可能是她当年在香港的同事
Perhaps when she was running things in Hong Kong.
她本人对此毫不知情
It is no idea what it all means?
你相信吗
And you believe that?
事实上 我们还不知道是谁盗窃名单
The truth is we don't have a clue of what's on the list...
也不知道目的何在
or what they are trying to do with it.
要不我们改天再谈
We can always do this later.
是吗 好吧
You know what? Let's.
我们先进行简单的词汇联想测验
I'd like to start with some simple words' sensations.
告诉我你首先想到的那个词
Just tell me the first word that punch into your head.
比如我说白天 你可能会说
For example I might day, and you might say...
浪费时间
Wasted.
好吧
All right.
枪支
Gun.
射击
Shot.
特工
Agent.
密探
Provocative.
女人
Woman.
麻烦
Provocatrix.
心脏
Heart.
目标
Target.
小鸟
Bird.
天空
Sky.
M夫人
M.
该死
Bitch.
阳光
Sunlight.
游泳
Swim.
月光
Moonlight.
跳舞
Dance.
杀人
Murder.
工作
Employment.
国家
Country.
英国
England.
天幕坠落
Skyfall.
够了
Done.
表现真不错
This is going well.
把这个拿去分析
Get these analyzed.
交给M夫人
When arrives, on me.
她可以见你了
She's ready for you.
对不起 我们认识吗
I'm sorry. Have we met before?
应该是我跟你说对不起
I am the one who should say "sorry".
我断了四根肋骨
It was only four ribs.
还受了多处内伤
There's nonetheless vital organs.
小意思
Nothing major.
是不是在伊斯坦布尔玩腻了
No enough excitement in Istanbul?
我调动岗位了
I've been reassigned.
暂时停止一线特工的工作
Temporary suspension from field work.
真的    嗯
Really?    Mmm.
可能和误杀007有关
Something to do with killing 007.
那一枪你打得很准
Well, you gave it your best shot.
其实我打得一点也不准
It was hardly my best shot.
再准我可能就回不来了
I'm sure I can survive your best.
我没想到你能活着回来
Time you'll get the chance.
帮个忙 好不好
Would you do me a favor, will you?
如果他们再让你回一线工作
If they'll do let you back out there...
先来通知我一声
Warn me first.
我在过渡期内担任马洛瑞的助理
I'm assisting Gareth Mallory in the transition...
然后就回一线工作
and then I'll be back in the field.
你自己要求的
That's what you want?
是的 当然
Yes, of course.
不是谁都能干一线
This is not for everyone.
啊 007
Ah, 007...
请吧
It's this way.
你也不容易
In your defense...
活动目标的确不好打
a moving target is much harder to hit.
那你最好就一直活动着
Then you better keep moving.
整个办公室都炸飞了 那镇纸却保留下来了
The whole office goes off in smoke and that bloody thing survives.
你提供的办公用品始终都很受欢迎 007
Your interior decorating tips have always been appreciated, 007.
007 盖勒斯・马洛瑞
007, Gareth Mallory.
希望我没有来得太晚 首相一直喋喋不休
I hope I haven't miss anything that P.M. does prattle in line of a crisis.
邦德
Bond.
马洛瑞
Mallory.
我看了邦德的测验结果
I have just been reviewing Bond's tests.
你好像通过了 不过很勉强
Seems you passed. Mind the scheme of your tiff?
你可以回来工作了
You're back on active service.
祝贺你
Congratulations.
谢谢
Thank you.
那我先告辞了
I'll be outside.
我还有个问题
I may have one question.
为什么不继续装死
Why not stay dead?
那样你可以全身而退
You have the perfect way out.
找个地方安度晚年
Go and live quietly somewhere.
很少一线特工能如此干脆地脱身
Not many field agents get to live this cleanly.
你在一线工作过吗
Do you get out in the field much?
我没打过老虎 可是我见过猫
You don't need to be an operative to see the obvious.
一线是年轻人的专利
It's a young men's game.
你受了严重的枪伤
Look, you've been seriously injured.
说自己能力不济 也在情理之中
There's no shame in saying you have lost a step.
别等到为时已晚 那才下不来台
The only shame, it would be not admitting until it's too late.
我下不下台 随你的便
I'm in, or fire me. Entirely up to you.
他说他准备好 就准备好了
If he says he is ready, he is ready.
也许你没说实话
Perhaps you can't see at all.
也许你不想说
Maybe you will.
你说这话是什么意思
What exactly are you implying?
你有些感情用事
You are sentimental about him.
只要我还在位一天
As long as I am the head of this department,
我就必须用自己的特工
I'll choose my own operatives.
人之常情
Fair enough.
祝你好运 007
Good luck, 007.
别把事情搞砸
Don't cock it out.
我们已经对那些弹片进行了分析
We've analyzed these shrapnel fragments.
幸亏不是直接命中 否则就把你劈成两半了
You're lucky it wasn't a direct hit. It would have cut you in half.
那是一种贫铀弹壳 属于军用级别的
It's a depleted uranium shell. A military grade.
非常罕见 极其昂贵
Hard to get, extremely expensive
只有少数人才有机会使用
and only used by select few.
看看 有没有面熟的
You recognize anyone?
他
Him.
好的 他叫帕特瑞斯
Okay, the name is Patrice.
是影子间谍
He's a ghost.
居住地和国籍不详
An unknown resident without country of origin.
怎么找到他
How do we find him?
不好找 幸亏我们在中情局还有几位朋友
Well, luckily I used to have one or two friends left in the CIA.
他们因为也门大使谋杀事件正在追捕他
They're after him for the Yemeni ambassador's murder.
就要得手了
And they're getting close.
根据情报 他最近要去上海两天 可能有什么事吧
Intel is he's gonna be in Shanghai in two days time. Probably a new job.
你先赶到那里 等候我的指示
You have to go there and wait further instructions.
如果他去了 马上逮捕
If he turns up, it's yours.
查清他为谁工作 名单在谁手里
Find out who he worked for and who has the list.
然后干掉他 为龙森
Then, terminate him for Ronson.
愿意效劳
With pleasure.
还有什么要说的吗
Is there anything else you want to tell me?
没了
No.
去找新任军需官 办理旅行文件
Report to the new quarter master for your documentation.
他还没有正式开张 坦纳会安排你们见面
He hasn't set up sharp yet, but Tanner will put you two together.
祝你好运
Good luck.
谢谢
Thank you.
007...
你真准备好了
You are ready for this?
是的 夫人
Yes, ma'am.
没想到邦德会通过测验
I didn't know Bond passed the tests.
他没通过
He didn't.
画名： 被拖去解体的战舰无畏号
作者： 约瑟夫・玛罗德・威廉・透纳  年代： 1839年
这幅画让人感觉很郁闷
Always makes me feel a little melancholy.
一艘战功赫赫的老战舰正要拖去被拆解
A grand whole warship being ignominiously hauled away for scrap.
这是时代的悲哀 你说呢
Inevitabilty of time, don't you think?
你看到什么
What do you see?
一艘军舰而已
A bloody big ship.
对不起
Excuse me.
007...
我是新来的Q先生
I'm your new Quarter master.
你在开玩笑
You must be joking.
因为我没穿工作服
Why, because I'm not wearing a lab coat?
因为你的胎毛还没褪干净
Because you still have spots.
俗话说 人不可貌相
My complexion is hardly relevant.
那是一般情况
And your confidence is.
年龄并不代表你有能力
Age is no guarantee of efficiency.
但是年轻代表你缺乏经验
And youth is no guarantee of innovation.
我只需要一支烟的功夫
Oh, how's it I can do more damage on my laptop
就能用身上这这台笔记本 把你用一年时间
sitting in my pajamas before my first cup of Earl Grey
在外面所做的种种努力 化为乌有
than you could do in a year in the field.
那还找我干嘛
So why do you need me?
总得有人用我的装备
Every now and then a trigger has to be pulled.
原来如此
Or not pulled.
看来计算机也不是万能的
It is hard to know which in your pajamas.
Q
007.
上海机票
Ticket to Shanghai.
旅行文件和护照
Documentation and passport.
谢谢
Thank you.
还有这个
And this.
瓦尔特PPKS 9毫米口径
Walter PPKS,  9mm short.
枪柄上带有微敏皮肤传感器
There's a micro dermal sensor in the grip...
上面有你的指纹 只有你能击发它
to your palm print, so only you can fire it.
它只效忠你个人 属于你自己的御用品
That's a random killing machine more than a personal statement.
这个呢
And this?
这是标配的无线发射器
Standard as your radio transmitter.
启动后能发射你所在的位置
Activated and broadcast your own location.
求救用的
Distress it.
就这些了
And that's it.
一把枪 一台无线电
A gun, and a radio.
好像还缺了点什么 对吗
Not exactly Christmas, is it?
是不是还想来颗钢笔炸弹
Were you expecting an exploding pen?
那些玩意儿早就过时了
We don't really go in for that any more.
祝你马到成功
Good luck out there in the field.
事后别忘了完璧归赵 谢谢
And please return the equipment in one piece.
世道变了
Brave new world.
上海
东西航空  226航班 晚上9点
名单在哪儿
Who got the list.
说 你为谁工作
Tell me, who you working for.
澳门
秘密特工
安德鲁・萨里 ＝ 维克多・尼基金
纳兹・侯赛因 ＝ 阿克萨・纳明
本・达希尔 ＝ 伊曼・马达基
保罗・英格利斯 ＝ 阿尔扬・德玛希
斯蒂夫・班勒尼沙 ＝ 埃莫瑞・卡萨
坦纳 他公开了前五个人名字
Tanner, he has posted the first five names.
他们已经暴露
Their cover is blown.
非常危险 通知他们撤回
They're in danger. Get them out now.
每周公布五个
想想你犯过的罪
澳门
客房服务
Room service.
我没叫服务
I didn't order anything.
也没叫你
Not even you.
我有一些新情报
I have got some new information.
让你传递情报 是不是大材小用了
Are not you a little too qualified to be delivering messages?
这是成长的必由之路
It's all part of the learning curve.
Q先生不敢坐飞机
And Q is afraid of flying.
谅他也不敢
Of course he is.
嗯 被盗窃的名单已经遭到解密
So, whoever stole the list has already decrypted it.
他们公布了前五个人的名字
They posted the first five names on the web.
那只是时间问题
It was only a matter of time.
这还只是开始
That should be the start.
他们每周公布五个人 以此类推
They're posting five more next week and the week after.
这很像是某种施虐游戏
It's some kind of sadistic game.
还用老式剃刀
Cutthroat razor.
未免也太老派了
How very traditional.
我一贯喜欢用老办法做事
Well, I'm going to do some things the old fashion way.
有时候还是老的好
Sometimes the old ways are the best.
你又想把性命交到我手里
Are you putting your life in my hands again?
M夫人已经把名单的事告诉我了
Tans, already briefed me on the list...
所以我很想知道 你来这儿的真正目的是什么
raising the tantalizing question of what you are really doing here.
我接到指令前来协助你
The official directive was to help
尽我所能
in anyway I can.
听上去是马洛瑞的密探
Like spying for Mallory.
马洛瑞其实没你你想的那么糟
You know, Mallory is not as bad as you think.
他是个官僚
He is a bureaucrat.
看来你没做好功课
You should do your homework.
盖勒斯・马洛瑞是一名中校
Gareth Mallory was Lieutenant Colonel
他在北爱尔兰赫里弗的团担任中校
Lieutenant Colonel in Northern Ireland Herford regiment.
曾经遭到爱尔兰共和军的监禁
He spent three months at the hands of the IRA.
所以看人不能只看外表
So there's more to him that meets the eye.
看里面
We'll see.
老实点
Keep still.
现在是关键时刻
This is the tricky part.
这下好多了
That's better.
这才是应有的面貌    嗯
You know the part now.    Mmh, mmh.
什么面貌
And what part is that?
老特工
Old dog
新面貌
new tricks.
晚上好
Good evening.
别老摸耳朵
Don't you touch your ear.
我找到三个出口
There are three exits.
还有一些盲点
And lots of blind spots.
他们已受我监控
I've got them covered.
你的礼服非常漂亮
You look beautiful in that dress.
你看起来也容光焕发
You could scrub out about yourself.
真想不到你的一双手竟然有如此大的魔力
It's amazing what one could do with an extra pair of hands.
您过奖了
You're telling mean.
喜欢赌博吗
You gamble?
偶尔喜欢小试牛刀
Don't like you a little flatten now and then?
谁不想碰碰运气呢
He doesn't like to take chances.
晚上好 先生 有什么可以帮您
Good evening, sir. How may I help you?
我想兑现这个
I'd like to cash these in, please.
好的 请稍等
One moment, sir.
祝你今晚好运 先生
Good fortune tonight, sir.
希望如此
Let's hope so.
这个 请你笑纳
With compliments of the house.
谢谢
Thank you.
总该请我喝一杯吧
Now you can afford to buy me a drink?
我得请你喝两杯
Maybe I could give a stretch or two.
现在我手上至少有四百万欧元
I guess I got good 4 million euros in here.
听着不错
Not bad.
我喜欢这个游戏
I like this game.
我们换一种好吗
Why don't we play another?
我不赌博
I don't gamble.
因为手气一向不好
I'm not very lucky.
有点像我上海的朋友
With lucky old friend in Shanghai.
我一直想看看是谁来兑现筹码
I've been waiting to see who'll redeem the chip.
没想到 竟然如此高调登台亮相
You made such a gold entrance into our little drama.
我是不是搅乱了剧情
Do I have a complicated plot?
剧情曲折才会引人入胜
Who doesn't appreciate the occasion of twists?
您是
Mr
邦德 詹姆斯・邦德
Bond. James Bond.
赛维琳 亲爱的邦德先生
Severing, so Mr. Bond
我们边喝酒边讨论下面的角色 好吗
shall we discuss your next performance with all that drink?
正合我意
Not bad.
你的朋友也参加吗
Are your friends be joining us?
我想 那是当然的
I'm afraid it's inevitable.
她很漂亮
She's pretty.
别多心
No, no.
可她过于招摇
Do you like that ass, don't you think?
我会随时通报
Well, I'll keep you posted.
不错
Perfect.
介意我问你一个商务问题吗
Would you mind if I ask you a business question?
得看什么问题
Depends on the question.
它关系到死亡
It has to do with death.
这种事你应该精通
A subject in which you're well versed.
你怎么知道
How would you know that?
只有一种女人会穿着露背装
Only a certain kind of woman wears a backless dress
在大腿上插一把伯莱塔70
with a Beretta 70 strapped to her thigh.
你不得不小心提防
One could never be too careful when
如果对面是穿礼服带瓦尔特的帅哥
a handsome man in tuxedos carry Walthers
是你杀了帕特瑞斯 我没猜错吧
I'm correct in assuming you'll killed Patrice?
是的
Yes.
能说说原因吗
Might I ask why?
我想见你们的老板
I want to meet your employer.
你可要三思后行
Be careful what you wish for.
你害怕了
You are scared.
谢谢你的款待
Thank you for the drink
邦德先生
Mr. Bond.
你表演很到位
You put on a good show.
不过你自打入座后
But ever since we sat down here
就一直在看你的保镖
you haven't stop looking at your bodyguards.
三个保镖未免过多
The three of them have been excessive.
他们在控制你
They're controlling you.
而非保护你
They're not protecting you.
你手腕上的纹身
Tattoo on your wrist
是澳门黑帮的标记
is Macao's sex trade..
你属于他们中的某个集团 多大了 12
You belonged to one of the houses when were you, 12?
13?
也许那帮人帮你赎身
I can see images of a way out.
也许你曾经爱过他
I hope she told you were in love.
不过已经时过境迁
But that was a long time ago.
我完全不懂你在说什么
You know nothing about it.
我知道女人恐惧时都会掩饰自己
I know when a woman is afraid and pretending not to be.
你对恐惧能有多少了解
How much do you know about fear?
全部
All there is.
你不了解我
Not like this.
你 也不了解他
And not like him.
我能帮你
I can help you.
我看未必
I don't think so.
一试便知
Let me try.
是吗
How?
带我去见他
Bring me to him.
你能杀掉他
Can you kill him?
是的
Yes.
你能吗
Will you?
八九不离十
Someone usually dies.
也许你能行
Perhaps you can.
我离开后 他们会来杀你
When I leave, they're going to kill you.
如果你能幸免 可以去找卡麦拉号
If you survive, I'm on the Kimera.
北港
North Harbour
7号泊位
Berth 7.
我们一个小时后离开港口
We cast off in an hour.
非常高兴认识你 邦德先生
Very nice to have met you, Mr. Bond.
祝您顺利
Good luck.
祝你好运
Good luck with that.
谢谢
Thank you.
全部押红
Put it all on red.
这就叫弱肉强食
That's the circle of life.
请进
Yes?
我们该动身了
It's time to cast off.
好啊
All right.
我更喜欢不带枪的女人
I like you better without putting you on red.
枪是我的衣服
I feel naked without it.
晚上好
Good evening.
围绕国防部能力的质疑
The controversy surrounding the Ministry of Defence
今天继续不断发酵
has escalated today
有关侯赛因暗杀事件的图像仍在网上疯传
as images of the Hussein assassination continue to circulate.
请注意 这些图像可能会引发观众的不安情绪
We should warn you, some viewers might find these images disturbing.
侯赛因上尉 是潜伏在中东的军情六处特工
Captain Hussein, an MI6 operative embedded in the Middle East
他是五名曝光的特工之一 目前这场内部泄密危机
was one of the five agents exposed in what is now been considered
在英国现代史上可以说是绝无仅有
the greatest internal security breach in modern British history.
英国首相表示 他将会继续力挺军情六处
The Prime Minister continues to express public support for MI6
而反对党的立场则是
while the opposition has taken the position
我们像一群迷失了方向的士兵
has taken the position where a bunch of antiquate bloody idiots
正在打一场我们既不熟悉也不可能取胜的战争
are fighting a war we don't understand and can't possibly win.
我已经损失三名特工
Look, three of my agents are dead already.
请不要再让我卷入政治斗争
Don't you bring me in politics now.
首相下令召开听证会
The Prime Minister has ordered an inquiry.
你必须出席
You'll have to appear.
你想让我当众受辱吗
Standing in the stocks of midday?
是谁迷失了方向
Who is antiquated now?
看在上帝份上 请你冷静点
For Christ sake, listen to yourself.
我们是民主国家 我们要对选民负责
We are a democracy and are accountable to the people we are trying to defend.
我们不能永远生活在神秘中
We can't keep working in the shadows.
现在没有神秘可言了
There are no more shadows.
你还不明白
You don't get this, do you.
那个幕后黑手 他很了解我们
Whoever is behind this, whoever is doing it, he knows us.
他曾经是我们的人
He is one of us.
他和邦德一样从神秘中走来
He comes from the same place as Bond.
你却说神秘不存在
The place you say doesn't exist.
它存在
The shadows.
现在还不算晚 回头还来得及
It's not too late. We could turn back now.
我看没那么容易
I wouldn't be so sure.
岛上居民一夜之间就跑光了
They abandoned it almost in the night.
他散布谣言说化工厂发生了泄漏
He made them think there was a leak at the chemical plant.
想不到一台计算机竟然能造成这么大的恐慌
It is amazing the panic you can cause with a single computer.
他想要这个岛
He wanted the island.
于是就要了
So he took it.
他是不是想要什么就有什么
Does he always get what he wants?
还不止如此
More than you know.
我们到了
对不起
I'm sorry.
你好 詹姆斯 欢迎
Hello, James. Welcome.
喜欢这座岛吗
You like the island?
我祖母也有一座岛
My grandmother had an island.
不过小得可怜
Nothing to boast off.
一小时就能走完
You could walk along within an hour.
可它依然是我们全家的天堂
But still it was, it was a paradise for us.
有年夏天 我们去岛上度假
One summer, we went for a visit
结果发现 岛上所有地方都布满了老鼠
and discovered the place had been infested with rats.
它们跟随渔船上岛 椰子是它们的美食
They'd come on a fishing boat and gorged themselves on coconut.
怎么样才能把老鼠赶走呢
So, how do you get rid of the rats on an island?
我祖母有办法
My grandmother showed me.
她把油桶埋到地下 桶盖装上合页
We buried an whole drum and changed the lead.
然后在上面绑些椰子充当诱饵
Then we wired the coconut to the lead as bait
老鼠就会去吃椰子 嘣嘣嘣嘣
and the rats will come for the coconut, and
于是掉进了桶里
They would fall into the drum.
一个月之后 岛上的老鼠就绝迹了
And after a month you've trapped all the rats.
可是接下来怎么办
But what did you do then?
把油桶扔进海里
Throw the drum into the ocean?
把它烧掉 不
Burn it? No
你就把它放在那儿
You just leave it
等老鼠们饿极了
and they begin to get hungry.
彼此之间
And one by one
就会互相残杀
they start eating each other
最后只能剩下两只 两个幸存者
until there are only two left, the two survivors.
然后怎么办 杀了它们 不
And then what, do you kill them? No.
你把它们拿出来 丢进树丛里
You take them and release them into the trees.
此时它们已经不再吃椰子了
And now they don't eat coconut any more.
它们只吃老鼠
Now they only eat rat.
你改变了它们的天性
You have changed their nature.
我们就是
The two survivors.
M选择的幸存者
This is what you made us.
我只听从自己的选择
I made my own choices.
嗯 你自以为是
You think you did.
这是她的过人之处
That's sheer genius.
香港站
Station H.
对吗 香港
Am I right, Hong Kong?
嗯
Mm hmm.
从86年到97年
'86 to '97.
那时我是她的宠儿
Back then, I was her favourite.
作为特工 你比我差远了
And you're not nearly the agent I was.
请恕我直言
I can tell you that.
瞧瞧你
Just look at you.
现在支撑你的只剩下药物
Barely held together by your pills,
还有酒精
and your drink.
可是我仍旧爱着自己的国家
Don't forget my pathetic love of country.
你还像信任妈妈一样信任M
You're still clinging to your faith in that old woman
而她只会对你撒谎
when all she does is lie to you.
她从没对我撒谎
She never lied lied to me.
没有   没有
No?    No.
知道你的射击考核得了多少分吗
What do you score on your maximum ship evaluation?
哈哈哈
Ha ha ha
40.
她说心理学家同意你复职  对吗
Did she tell you the psychologist cleaned you for duty?
是的    错
Yes.    No.
错了
No.
医学评估 不及格
Medical evaluation; Failed.
体能评估 不及格
Physical evaluation; Failed.
心理评估 有酒精和药物成瘾症状表现
Psychological evaluation, alcohol and substance addiction indicated.
对权威表现出病理性拒斥
Pathological rejection of authority
源于未经治愈的儿童创伤史
based on unresolved childhood trauma.
不同意该评测对象返回一线工作
Subject is not approved for field duty
建议立即停止其一切职务 我的天呐
and immediate suspension from service advised.
这不是撒谎 是什么呢
What is this, if not betrayal?
她明知你状态不佳 还派你来抓我
She send you off to me, knowing that you're not ready
让你来送死
knowing you will likely die.
最毒不过妇人心呐
Mommy was very bad.
嗯
Hmm?
哦 天呐
Ooh.
瞧她对你干了什么
See what she's done to you?
可她从没把我绑在椅子上
Well, she never tied me to a chair.
真遗憾
I loss.
你是在说她吗
Are you sure this is about her?
当然说她
It's about her
还有你 和我
and you and me.
我们是最后那两只老鼠
You see, we are last two rats.
我们要么彼此残杀
We can either eat each other.
嗯
Hmm?
要么去杀别人
Or eat everyone else.
仔细想想你曾经接受过的训练
How you're trying to remember your training now?
这样做 需要哪些规则
What's the regulation to cover this?
凡事都有第一次 对吗
Well, first time for everything.
嗯 你怎么知道我这是第一次呢
Yes. What makes you think this is my first time?
哦 邦德先生
Oh, Mr. Bond
你整天跑来跑去无聊透了 无聊透顶
All the physical stuff's so dull. So dull.
追杀间谍
Changing spies.
哦 都什么年代了
So oldfashioned.
也不怕得关节炎
Your knees must be killing you.
英格兰
England
大英帝国 军情六处
the Empire, MI6.
你生活在一片废墟
You're living in the ruins as well.
只是你浑然不知
You just don't know it yet.
在我这儿 至少没有老太婆发号施令
At least here there are no old ladies giving orders
以及
and no little
啵
Bip!
那些小玩意儿和Q军需官
gadgets from those fools in Q branch.
如果愿意
If you'd want it,
你可以自己选择自己的任务
you could pick your own secret missions
就像我
as I do.
说说吧
Name it.
想做什么
通过操纵股票来击某家跨国公司 砰 容易
You destabilize a multinational by manipulating stocks. Bip. Easy.
中止喀布尔上空的间谍卫星发送信号
Interrupt transmission from a spy satellite over Kabul.
搞定
Done.
嗯 还可以操纵乌干达选举 只要有人肯出大价钱
Hmm.  Rig an election in Uganda. All to the highest bidder.
或者制造伦敦爆炸案
Or a gas explosion in London.
只需点一下鼠标
Just point and click.
俗话说 人各有志
Well, everyone needs a hobby.
说说你的志向
So what's yours?
再次复活
Resurrection.
让你长长见识
Let me show you something.
这很说明问题 对吗
Tells a story, doesn't it?
人们离岛时过于匆忙
They left the island so quickly
不知道该带走什么 留下什么 什么最重要
that couldn't decide what to take what to leave, what was important.
每天看到这些都会提醒我 做事一定要抓住重点
And this every day reminds me to focus on the essentials.
知道吗 詹姆斯 在我的生活中没有多余的东西
There is nothing nothing superfluous in my life.
一件东西变得多余了 我就 砰 随手扔掉
When a thing is redundant, it is eliminated.
五十年的麦卡伦
Fifty years old McCullan.
我觉得应该最适合你的口味
A particular favorite of yours, I understand?
那么 为谁干杯
So what's the toast?
为我们爱的女人
To the women we love?
亲爱的
Darling
亲爱的 爱人来了
Darling, your love is out here.
不不不不
No, no, no, no
站直了 别动 千万别动
Stand up straight, keep still
玩什么都行 就是
and whatever you do, don't lose your head.
不能
Don't lose. . .
玩命
your head.
不要动 好吗
Don't lose your head.
现在该为你的射击成绩雪耻了
Time to redeem your maximum ship scores.
来吧
Let's see.
看谁先打掉
You can be the first
她头上的酒杯
to knock the gloss from her head.
为了公平起见 我让你先打
And just to be sporting, I'll let you go first.
我们看看谁是赢家
Let's see who it's up on top.
哦 天呐
Oh, can't believe it.
我的老天爷
Can't believe it.
你真的还活着吗
Did you really die that day?
在这个世界上到底还有没有007这个人物
Is there any, any of the old 007 left?
该我了
My turn.
我赢了 还有什么可说的
I win. What do you say to that?
可惜了那杯威士忌
So waste of good scotch.
现在你想干什么
What are you going to do now?
把我带回去 就你一个人
Take me back to her? All on your own?
谁说我一个人
Who says I'm on my own?
军需官的最新玩意儿
Latest thing from Q branch.
无线发射器
On the radio.
好吧 到时候了
All right, time to say hello.
我印象中你应该很高大
You are smaller than I remembered.
我对你没有任何印象
Well, as I bet you remember you were tall.
奇怪 我觉得我们好像刚刚分手
Strange, for me it feels just like yesterday.
感到意外吗
Are you surprised?
不怎么意外
Not particularly.
你从来都不会安分守己
But then you always were a slippery one.
也许那正是你喜欢我的原因
Maybe that's why you liked me so much.
你未免太不谦虚了
You flatter yourself.
毫无悔意
No remorse.
我早料到会这样的
Just as I can imagine it.
后悔不是我的风格
Regret is unprofessional.
哈哈哈哈
Ha ha ha ha
后悔不是你的风格
"Regret is unprofessional"
他们把我关了整整五个月 不让我见任何人
They kept for five months in a room with no air.
严格审查
They tortured me.
我始终保守秘密 不肯把你供出来
And I ain't protected your secrets. I protected you.
可是我心里很痛苦
But they made me suffer
非常痛苦
and suffer
痛苦极了
and suffer.
直到后来我才弄清楚
Until I realized
就是你 出卖了我
it was you who betrayed me.
你出卖了我
You betrayed me.
天呐 你的无情让我感到万念俱灰
So I had only one thing left.
我的氰化物胶囊藏在左侧的臼齿中
My cyanide capsule in my back lift molar.
你记得的 对吗
You remember, right?
于是我就咬破了胶囊
So I broke the tooth
氰化物流出来 瞬间
and bit into the capsule.
我感觉五脏俱焚
Burned all my insights
但是我没死
but I didn't die.
鬼使神差我活了下来
Life clinged to me like a disease.
后来
And then
后来 我明白了
I understood
为什么我没死
why I had survived.
因为我得最后一次看上再你一眼 对吧
I needed to look in your eyes one last time.
希望我没有让你失望
Well, I hope it was worth it.
席尔瓦先生
Mr. Silva
你将被送往贝尔玛仕监狱关押
you are going to be transferred to Belmarsh Prison
你会一直待在那里
where you'll be remanded in custody
直至皇家检察署最终裁定 你是何
until the Crown Prosecution Service deem you fit to stand trial for. . .
请叫我的名字 拜托
Say my name. Say it.
我的本名
My real name.
你一定还记得
I know you remember it.
那个名字镌刻在被你炸毁的建筑物纪念墙上
Your name is on the memorial wall of the very building you attacked.
我会把它抹掉
I will have it struck off.
很快 你的过去将会消失 就如同你的未来
Soon, your past will be as nonexistent as your future.
我们不会再见面了
I'll never see you again.
你知道它对你意味着什么吗
Did you know what it does to you?
我是说氰化物
Hydrogen cyanide?
看看你的杰作
Look at what you've done,
妈妈
Mother
告诉我 他电脑里都有什么
Let's me know what you recover from its computers.
他是否发送过那份名单 给什么人
Has he transmitted the list? If such, to who.
马上去搞清楚
I want this resolved.
是 夫人
Yes, ma'am.
他真名叫迪亚戈・罗德里格斯
His name is Tiago Rodriguez.
曾经是名优秀特工
He was a brilliant agent.
因为他擅自做了超越职权的事
But he started operating beyond his brief hacking the Chinese.
香港移交临近 中国人开始追捕他
The hand over was coming up and they were hunting him, so
我只好放弃他
I gave him up.
用他换回六名特工
I got six agents in return
和平稳过渡
and a peaceful transition.
我们该走了 夫人 听证会半小时内开始
We should go, ma'am. Board inquiry begins in 30minutes.
我要知道他电脑里有什么
I want to know what's on that computer.
下面 请看看席尔瓦的电脑
Now, looking at Silva's computer
他似乎做过很多令人感到不可思议的事
it seems to me he's done a number of slightly unusual things.
他利用安全故障协议
It's established failed saved protocols
清除存储器中的信息 以防止文件受到访问
to wipe the memory if there's any attempt to access certain files.
全世界只有六个人能够编写那种保护程序
Only about six people in the world can program safe guides like that.
当然了 能绕过去吗
Of course there are. Can you get past them?
让你问着了
I invented them.
搞定
Right then.
看看你都有什么 席尔瓦先生
Let's see what you got for us Mr. Silva.
进去了
We're in.
先生
Sir
你看这些是什么
What do you make of this?
是他的奥米茄网址
This is Omega site.
是用最复杂的编码
What encrypted level it has.
似乎是模糊处理编码 用以隐藏真实目的
Looks like overstated code to consider its true purpose.
属于模糊安全方式
Security through obscurity.
女士们先生们 请安静
Ladies and gentlemen, if I might have order.
我宣布听证会开始
I'd like to begin the proceedings.
今天我们在这里讨论重要议题
We are gathered today to adjust some important issues
事关我们国家未来的国防安全
concerning the future of our national security.
想出去了
Going somewhere?
这么说 在军情六处最近的危机中 你认为自己的管理
So you believe your stewards of MI6 during the recent crisis
非常到位
has been up to scratch?
目前我们已经将肇事者缉拿归案
Well, I believe we have apprehended the responsible party
而且我们也已经采取了必要措施
undertaking all the necessary steps
保证敏感信息不再被泄露
to ensure that the sensitive information is contained.
呵 看来你干得很出色
Ugh! Such a job well done.
当然 也不能说没有问题
I'm not saying it all gone perfectly, but
请原谅我没有为你庆功
You forgive me for not putting up the bunting.
不过那些重大泄密和特工死亡的事件  也很难令人忘怀
I find rather difficult to overlook the monumental security breaches
应该说 那是你一手造成的
and dead operatives which you were singled handedly responsible.
他是用了多态变形引擎 使代码发生变异
He's using a polymorphic engine to mutate the code.
当我试图访问时 它会改变
Whenever I try to gain an access, it changes.
就像魔方一样 令人难以琢磨
It's like solving the Rubik's cube that's fighting back.
停
Stop.
拉进去
Go into that.
格兰博格
Grandsborough
格兰博格路
Granborough Road, it's an old
大都会线的古老车站之一
tube station on the metropolitan line.
已经关闭多年
Been closed for years.
用它做关键词
Use that as a key.
哦 看呐 一张地图
Now, look. It's a map.
是伦敦
It's London.
地下伦敦
Subterranean London.
怎么回事
What's going on?
门为什么打开了
Why the doors open?
哦 天呐
Oh, no.
谁能告诉我 他是怎么进系统的
Can someone tell me how the hell he got into our system?
你是一个笨小孩
哦 见鬼
Oh, shit.
见鬼 见鬼 见鬼
Shit, shit, shit.
他黑了我们
He acted this.
哦 不
Oh, no.
Ｑ
Q
他跑了
He is gone.
我在隔壁牢房下面的楼梯间内
I'm on the stairway of the low isolation.
收到没有 Q
Are you with me, Q?
收到 正在找你
I can hear you. I'm looking for you.
找到了 现在开始跟踪
I've got him. Tracking the location.
继续向前
Just keep looking forward.
进入右手的安全门
Enter the next service door on your right.
进了安全门 就能看到地铁
If you enter through that door, you should be in the tube.
我看到了
I'm in the tube.
邦德 这不是越狱 是精心策划的阴谋
Bond, this isn't an escape. This was years in the planning.
他故意让我们抓到他 而且让我们进入他电脑
He wanted us to capture him, he wanted us to access his computers.
这都是计划好的
It was all planned.
炸毁总部大楼 掌握我们的应急预案
Blowing up HQ, only emergency protocols.
知道我们会迁到此地
And all we have retrieved down here.
这我都清楚
I got all that.
我只关心他下一步要干什么
What it's got planned next it worries me.
区域线离你最近
The district line is the closest,
左手有个安全门
there should be a service door on your left.
找到了
Got it.
打不开
It won't open.
你得使出吃奶的劲儿
Of course it will. Put your back into it.
你来吃个奶给我看看
Why don't you come down here and put your back into it?
不 卡死了
No, it's studded.
噢 坏了
Not good.
有列车来了
There's a train coming.
嗯 看来不妙
Hmm. That's vexing.
我没事了
I'm through.
我说嘛
I told you.
但是触发了报警器 会惊动警察
We've alerted security. Police are on the way.
你在哪儿
Where are you now?
在圣殿教堂车站~
Temple tube station.
没见过这么多人
Along with half of London.
看到了 你在那儿
Oh I see. Here you are.
我知道我在哪儿 Q
I know where I am, Q.
他在哪儿
Where is he?
请稍等 我在找
Give us a second. I'm looking for him.
人太密了 我看不到他
There's too many people. I can't see him.
这正是伦敦地铁的高峰
Welcome to rush hour on the tube.
对你是全新的体验
Something you don't know much about.
列车要出站了
The train's leaving.
我上不上车
Do I get on the train?
先别上 还不能确定他在不在车上
Don't get on the train unless he's on it. Give us a minute.
到底上不上车
Tell me if I get on the train.
邦德
Bond
什么
What?
立刻上车
Get on the train.
他家一定有急事儿
He's keen to get home.
打开车门 好吗
Open the door, please.
请你开门
Open the door.
安全局的 抱歉
I'm from Safety. Carry on.
你在哪儿
Where are you?
你猜猜看 Q
Take a wild guess, Q.
他化了妆 身穿警察制服
He's in disguise, now. Disguised as a policeman.
那当然
Of course he is.
他要去哪儿
Where is he going?
他要去哪儿啊
M有危险
He's going for M.
通知坦纳 让她马上转移
Tell Tanner. Get her out of there.
你忽略了 或者说故意忽略了
You overlooked or chosen to ignore
确凿的证据
hard evidence
你自始至终 顽固地坚持说
and consistently, almost obstantly
席尔瓦跑了
Silva has escaped.
邦德正在追他
Bond's in pursuit.
我们必须立刻送你到安全的地方 夫人
We need to get you to a secured location immediately, ma'am.
我不可能离开这个地方
Like hell am I going to show him my back.
您是不是坐不住了
Are we straining your attention?
没有 抱歉 夫人 请继续
No. Please, Minister. Proceed.
对不起
Excuse me.
闪开 闪开
Move! Move!
您怎么还能一直生活在
It's as if you insist on pretending
间谍黄金时代的虚幻梦境中
we still live in the golden age of espionage,
把你的情报人员当成唯一的主角
when human intelligence was the only resource available.
那是一种完全过时的思维
Well, I find this rather oldfashioned belief
说明你根本就无视飞速发展的当今世界
demonstrates a reckless disregard for every
对不起 夫人 我不想打断您 不过
Excuse me, Minister. I don't mean to interrupt but
为了多听取意见
Just for the sake of variety,
是不是应该请证人发言了
might we actually hear from the witness?
当然
Of course.
谢谢
Thank you.
噢
Oh !
这次我不会再失手 席尔瓦先生
I won't miss next time, Mr. Silva.
不错
Not bad.
真不错 詹姆斯 你真是不减当年
Not bad, James, for a physical wreck.
哦 谢谢
Oh, thank you.
你抓到我了
You caught me.
请 接受奖赏
Now, here's your prize.
这是我在玩具商店找到的玩意儿
The latest thing from my local toy store.
名字叫做 无线电
It is called "radio".
喔
Whew!
这个对我不管用
I do hope that wasn't for me.
对
No.
那个管用
But that is.
主席先生 各位委员
Chairman, Ministers
今天我听到很多人都提到
Today I've repeatedly heard how
我们的部门有多么无足轻重
irrelevant my department has become.
我们要特工干什么 为什么代号是00
Why you we need agents for DoubleO section.
感觉匪夷所思
Isn't that all rather quaint?
不过 我的看法和诸位完全不同
Well, I suppose I see a different world than you do.
我看到的情景让我非常震惊
And the truth is that what I see frightens me.
我震惊是因为 我们现在不知道谁是敌人
I'm frightened because our enemies are not longer known to us.
你们在地图上找不到他们
They do not exist on the map.
他们没有国籍
They're not nations.
他们各自为战
They are individuals.
看看你们周围 感到害怕吗
But look around you, who do you fear?
某种面孔 服装 旗帜 不会
Can you see a face, a uniform, a flag? No.
我们的世界没有变得更加透明
Our world is not more transparent now.
而是更加模糊
It's more opaque.
他们躲在阴暗处
It's in the shadows.
我们必须在黑暗中战斗
That's where we must do battle.
当你们说我们无足轻重时 请扪心自问
So, before you declare us irrelevant, ask yourselves:
你们感到安全吗
How safe do you feel?
顺便说一句
Just one more thing to say.
我过世的丈夫非常喜爱诗歌
My late husband was a great lover of poetry.
我也
And, um. . .
耳濡目染感受了些 尽管算不上喜欢
I suppose some of it sunk in, despite my best intentions.
今天
And here today,
让我想起一首诗 好像是丁尼生的
I remember this. I think, from Tennyson.
如今我们已经年老力衰
We are not now that strength
再也不见当年的风采
which in old days moved earth and heaven.
历历往事如烟
That which we are, we are.
岁月如霜 命运多蹇
One equal temper of heroic hearts.
常使英雄 心寒 气短
Made weak by time and fate,
但豪情不减
but strong in will
我将 不懈努力 求索
to strive, to seek, to find
战斗到永远
and not to yield.
快 快 快 快
Go, go, go, go!
出去
Move.
出去 快 出去
Move! Go! Move!
007 你想干什么
007, what the hell are we doing?
绑架我吗
You're kidnapping me.
你要这么说 也可以
That would be one way of looking at it.
太多人会因为我丢掉性命
Too many people are dying because of me.
如果他想杀你 一定会来找你
If you wants you, he's gonna have to come and get you.
我们自始至终都比席尔瓦晚一步
We've been one step behind Silva from the start.
这一次 我们会走在他的前面
It's time to get out in front and change the game.
拿我当钓饵
And I'm to be the bait?
好吧
All right.
只有你我 没有别人
Just us. No one else.
Q 我需要帮助
Q, I need help.
我在跟踪你 你要去哪儿
I'm tracking the car. Where are you going?
我和M 我们即将消失
I got M. We're about to disappear.
什么
What?
请你在我走过的路上留下痕迹
I need you to lay a trail of breadcrumbs
但不能被人察觉 除了席尔瓦
impossible to follow for anyone except Silva.
能办到吗
You think you can do it?
我想这应该不是官方行动
I'm guessing this isn't strictly official.
完全不是
Not even remotely.
看来我在特工界的前程将毁于一旦
So much for my promising career in espionage.
我不想藏在这儿 如果这是你的伟大计划
Well, I'm not hiding in there if that's your brilliant plan.
我们得换辆车
We're changing vehicles.
公务车的麻烦 是总带有跟踪器
The trouble with company cars is they have trackers.
哦 这辆车未免有点太过夸张
Oh, and I suppose that's completely inconspicuous.
请上车
Get in.
这车坐着不舒服
It's not been accountable, is it?
你是不是还想抱怨
Are you going to complain the whole way?
哦 把我弹出去好了
Oh, go on and eject me.
我不在乎
See if I care.
我们去哪儿
Where are we going?
回到过去
Back in time.
回到我们最风光的年代
Somewhere we'll have the advantage.
这很微妙
It's a fine line.
痕迹太细 将会难以分辨
If a breadcrumb's too small then he might miss it.
反之 席尔瓦很可能会看出破绽
Too big and Silva will smell the rat.
你确定 就连席尔瓦也能注意到吗
That's what you think, even Silva will be able to spot that?
只有他能注意到
He's the only one who could.
长官
Sir
哦
Oh.
你们在干什么
What are you doing?
我们 在监视
We're just. . .monitoring.
你们在制作引诱席尔瓦的虚假跟踪信号
Creating a false tracking signal for Silva to follow.
这个 长官
Well, sir
好想法 将他信号隔离
Excellent thinking. Get them isolated.
让他上9号公路 那路很直
Send him on the A9. It's the direct route.
你们可以用交通摄像头监视他
You can monitor his progress more accurately
并随时加以确认
and confirm it with the traffic cameras.
可是 首相发现了怎么办
But what if PM finds out?
那只能自认倒霉
Then, we're all buggered.
继续吧
Carry on.
苏格兰
这是你生长的地方
This is where you grew up?
嗯
Mm.
父母去世的时候你有多大
How old were you when you died?
答案你知道
You know the answer to that.
你对一切了如指掌
You know the whole story.
孤儿最适合干我们这行
Orphans always make the best recruits.
要下雨了
The storm's coming.
天幕庄园
天呐    嗯
Christ.    Mm hmm.
难怪你从不回家
I wonder you never came back.
詹姆斯
James
詹姆斯・邦德
James Bond.
上帝啊
Good God.
你还活着
You're still alive.
见到你 也很高兴
Nice to see you too.
M 他是金凯德
M this is Kincade.
我们家的猎场看守人
Kincade is keeping here since I was a boy.
很高兴见到你 艾玛
Please to meet you, Emma.
金凯德先生
Mr. Kincade.
你来晚了一步
You're a tad late.
他们以为你死了 就把这儿卖了
They sold the place when they thought you were dead.
看来他们错了
Seems they were wrong.
你回来干什么
What are you doing here?
有人想要杀我们
Some men are coming to kill us.
不过 我们会先杀掉他
We're gonna kill them first.
那得做好准备
Then we'd better get ready.
军械库还在吗
Do we still have a gun room?
啊
Ah.
他们把那些枪支 卖给了一个爱达荷州的收藏家
They sold a lot to a collector from Idaho or some such place.
两周前就运走了
They were shipped up weeks ago.
这里只剩了 你父亲用过的双筒猎枪
There's just your father's old hunting rifle.
我们不肯卖掉
We couldn't let that go.
我们只能靠它了
And this is what we've got.
也许还有一些采石场用的雷管
There might be a couple of sticks of dynamite from the quarry.
即便什么都没剩下 有时候
But if all else fails, sometimes
老法子 也一样管用
the old ways are the best.
我们的对手是什么人
So, who are we supposedly fighting?
别说我们 金凯德
No "we", Kincade.
这事跟你无关
This is not your fight.
你不带我玩 试试 反了你了
Try to stop me, you jumpedup little shit.
别忘了 是我教你 扣扳机不要用力
Now, remember what I taught to you. Don't let it pull to the left.
我会尽力而为
I'll do my best.
你说靠什么混饭来着
What did you say you did for a living?
艾玛
Emma
我给你拿来一样东西
I brought you some things.
这里晚上很冷
The nights get cold here.
谢谢 金凯德先生
Thank you, Mr. Kincade.
这老房子真漂亮
It's a beautiful old house.
当然
She is.
她就像个老年贵妇
And like all great ladies,
收藏了很多很多秘密
she still has her secrets ways.
你先看看这个
Let me show you this.
地道
A priest hole.
是的 宗教革新时代就有了
Yes, from Reformation times.
这地道通往外面的沼泽
The tunnel leads under the moor.
有危险 就可以用它逃生
If you get in danger, this is the place to come.
那天晚上 我把他父母的死讯告诉他
The night I told him his parents have died
他在里面待了整整两天
he's hidden here for two days.
从这儿出来以后
But he did come out.
他就长大了
He was no boy any more.
啊 干活吧
Eh. Must get on.
炸药
这事都怪我 对吗
I fucked this up, didn't I?
不
No.
你在履行职责
You did your job.
我看了你给我写的讣告
I read your obituary of me.
是吗
And?
很震惊
Appalling.
是啊 我知道你不喜欢
Yeah, I knew you'd hate it.
坚韧不拔 英国精神的代表
It called you 'An example of the British fortitude.'
那倒没什么
I think that was all right.
准备好了吗
Are you ready?
还没你的时候我就准备好了 孩子
I was ready before you're were born, son.
苏格兰欢迎你们
Welcome to Scotland.
你掉东西了
You dropped something?
伤哪儿了
Are you hurt?
伤了自尊心了
Only my pride.
我枪法一直很糟
I never was a good shot.
他没来这儿
He's not here,
and he's not here.
他总想搞点名堂
Always good at making an entrance.
你们两个快去厨房 马上
You two, go to the kitchen. Now!
去拱门后面
Go behind the yard.
去教堂 利用地道
Go to the chapel. Use the tunnel.
都给我听好了 谁也不许碰她
Everyone listen to me. Don't you dare touch M.
她是我的
She's mine.
能让他出来见个面吗
And your friends come out and say 'hello'?
来吧 这边
Come on. This way.
终于可以说再见了
I always hated this place.
你觉得暖和吗
Are you getting warm?
去找到邦德的尸体
Just make sure Bond is dead.
就剩下我们俩了
Now it's me and her.
你这样疲于奔命的有什么意义吗 邦德先生
You see what comes of all this running around, Mr. Bond?
像这样 追来杀去
All this jumping and fighting.
太辛苦了
It's exhausting.
放松点
Relax.
你需要放松
You need to relax.
哦 妈妈在叫你呢
Well, mother's calling.
我替你去跟她吻别吧
I'll give her a goodbye kiss for you.
缅怀 安德鲁・邦德 莫妮卡・德拉卡洛娃・邦德
非常好
Of course.
这里最合适
It had to be here.
就该这样结束
It had to be this way.
谢谢
Thank you.
我找不到    你别动
I can't find it, though.    No.
请你
Please.
别动
Don't.
你受伤了 怎么搞的
You're hurt. You're hurt.
他们怎么你了
What have they done to you?
把你弄成这样
让我们解脱吧
Free the both of us.
让我们都解脱
用同一颗子弹
With the same bullet.
开枪
Do it.
开枪啊
Do it!
只有你能这样
Only you can do it.
开枪
Do it!
现在只剩下我了
Last rat standing.
007.~
你为什么才来
What took you so long?
因为 湖里的水太深了
Oh, I got into some deep water.
看来这回
I suppose it's
真的没办法脱身了
too late to hang around and fret.
还想再试试
Well, I'm game if you are.
这件事我做对了
I did get one thing right.
喔
Wow.
我没想到你会上这儿来
I didn't even know you could come up here.
这里风景很美
I hate to waste a view.
我明白你意思
I can see why.
我以为你会返回一线工作
I thought you were going back out on active service.
我回绝了
I declined.
是你说的
You said it yourself.
不是谁都能干一线
Field works are not for everyone.
你很明智 这下我就安全了
If it helps, I feel a lot safer.
今天宣读她的遗嘱
Her will was read today.
她留给你这个
She left you this.
也许她想提醒你 该去坐办公室了
Maybe it was her way of telling you to take a desk job.
恰恰相反
Just the opposite.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们还从未正式介绍过彼此
You know, we've never formally been introduced.
哦
Oh.
我叫伊芙
My name is Eve.
伊芙・玛妮潘妮
Eve Moneypenny.
希望有一天我们能旧梦重温
I look forward to our time together, Miss Moneypenny.
我也是
Me too.
我们将来肯定还会有亲密接触
I'm sure we will have one or two clear shaves.
早上好 007
Good morning, 007.
早上好 坦纳
Good morning, Tanner.
他要见你
He will see you now.
胳膊好了吗 长官
How's the arm, sir?
什么 哦 快了
What? Oh, it's fine.
快好了
It'll get better.
这件事对非一线工作人员触动很大
All pretty shocking for someone unused to field work.
不过 007
So, 007
任重道远
Lots to be done.
你还愿意继续工作吗
Are you ready to get back to work?
我愿意 M
With pleasure, M.
我愿意
With pleasure.